Sometimes dreams come back to life.
The Rookie is a drama, family film directed by John Lee Hancock.
Jim Morris never made it out of the minor leagues before a shoulder
injury ended his pitching career twelve years ago.
Now a married-with-children high-school chemistry teacher and baseball coach in Texas, Jim's team makes a deal
with him: if they win the district championship, Jim will try out with a major-league organization.
The bet proves incentive enough for the team, and they go from worst to first,
making it to state for the first time in the history of the school.
Jim, forced to live up to his end of the deal, is nearly laughed off the try-out field--until he gets onto the mound, where he confounds the
scouts (and himself) by clocking successive 98 mph fastballs, good enough for a minor-league contract with the Tampa Bay Devil Rays.
Jim's still got a lot of pitches to throw before he makes it to The Show, but with
his big-league dreams revived, there's no telling where he could go.
Jimmy Morris, played by Dennis Quaid.
Lorri Morris, played by Rachel Griffiths.
Joaquin 'Wack' Campos, played by Jay Hernandez.
Olline, played by Beth Grant.
Hunter Morris, played by Angus T. Jones.
Jim Morris Sr., played by Brian Cox.
The Rookie is a 2002 American sports drama film directed by John
Lee Hancock and produced by Walt Disney Pictures.
It is based on the true story of Jim Morris who
debuted in Major League Baseball at age 35.
The film stars Dennis Quaid as Morris, alongside
Rachel Griffiths, Jay Hernandez, Angus T.
Jones, and Brian Cox.
It was released in the United States on March 29, 2002.
The movie was filmed in 2.40:1 widescreen.
The film explores themes of sports, parent child
relationship, baseball, life's dream, growing up.
The tone is emotional.